Finding Aid for the Edward Gordon Craig Papers LSC.1006
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Section Four: Published Articles and Reprints with Contributions by or Reference to Craig
  - De Casseres, Benjamin. Gordon Craig Comes to America; the First Work of the Famous Master of Reinhardt and Stanislavsk to Be Shown in the Tyler Production of Macbeth. Theatre Magazine, February 1931.; (2 leaves, clipped article) (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Simsonson, Lee. The Case of Gordon Craig. Theatre Guild Magazine., 1931.; (4 leaves, clipped article) (Box 6, Folder 21)
    Part one only; second part published in March issue, not available.
  - Sheringham, George. Scene Design in England. Theatre Guild Magazine, May 1931.; (3 leaves, clipped article) (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - The Life and Theatrical Career of Edmund Kean, 1787-1833; with a foreward by Gordon Craig [Bookseller's catalogue]. London: Ifan Kyrle Fletcher, 1938.; (62pp. Catalogue One, 2 copies) (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Bowen, Elizabeth. Book reviews. The Tatler and Bystander, February 9, 1949.; (1 leaf, clipped article) (Box 6, Folder 24)
    Photograph of Gordon Craig with notice of a new biography recently published: Janet Leeper's Edward Gordon Craig: Designs for the Theatre. London: Penguin Books, 1948.
  - Oenslager, Donald. Edward Gordon Craig: Artist of the Theatre, 1872-1966. A memorial exhibition in the Amsterdam Gallery. Bulletin of the New York Public Library, September and October 1967.; (36 leaves, photocopy) (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Goodman, Henry. Edward Gordon Craig: an Exhibit. UCLA Librarian (vol.20 no.10), Los Angeles, October 1967.; (1 leaf, clipped article) (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Program. International Institute for Theatre Research. Eighth International Course on Theatre History. Venice, September 10-23 1970.; (2 leaves) (Box 6, Folder 27)
    With this: listing of lectures, including one by Arnold Rood on Gordon Craig.
  - Rood, Arnold. After the Practice, the Theory: Gordon Craig and movement. Lecture presented at the Eighth International Course on Theatre History. Venice, September 12, 1970.; (21pp. Typescript (mimeograph), in French, Italian and English. One copy each) (Box 6, Folder 28)
    With this: Poster advertising the lecture by Rood.
  - Stewart, Ian. A Thousand and One Scenes: Gordon Craig and the Theatre. Country Life, February 10, 1972.; (1 leaf, clipped article) (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Newman, L.M. Resources for the Future Study of Edward Gordon Craig. International Federation for Theatre Research, 1974.; (19pp.) (Box 6, Folder 30)
- Section Five: Correspondence
  - Correspondence re Bethlehem
    Bethlehem - a nativity play by Laurence Housman performed with music by Joseph Moorat under the stage-direction of Edward Gordon Craig, December 1902
    - Baillie, John. Letters to Gordon Craig. v.p., 1902.; (9 items) (Box 7, Folder 1)
      Mr. Baillie served as stage manager for the production.
    - Business correspondence, miscellaneous. v.p., 1902-1903.; (5 items) (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Greet, Ben. Letters to Gordon Craig and Laurence Housman. v.p., 1902.; (2 items and 1 fragment) (Box 7, Folder 3)
      Letters concerning an American production of the play.
    - Housman, Laurence. Letters to Gordon Craig. v.p., 1902-1903.; (47 items) (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Moorat, Joseph. Letters to Gordon Craig. v.p., 1902.; (10 items) (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Production notes, miscellaneous. n.p., 1902.; (2 items) (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Shaw, Martin Fallas. n.p., 1902.; (1 item) (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Woodroffe, Paul. Letters to Gordon Craig. n.p., 1902.; (5 items) (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Craig, Edith. Letters to Charles Chenil & Company London, 1911.; (1 item) (Box 7, Folder 9)
    Written on behalf of her brother, Edward Gordon Craig.
  - Craig, Edith. Letters to Sarah Bernhardt. London, 1911.; (2 items) (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Craig, Edward Gordon. Letters to Various Persons. v.p., v.d.; (52 items)
    - Bocking, Miss [Bo] n.p., circa 1931.; (1 item) (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Carew, James. v.p., 1909-1910.; (4 items) (Box 7, Folder 12)
      Mr. Carew was a family friend.
    - Craig, Edith. Correspondence with Edward Gordon Craig. v.p., 1895-1930.; (19 items) (Box 7, Folder 13)
      Correspondence includes 15 letters from Craig to Edith Craig and four letters from Edith Craig to Craig.
      Edith Craig (Edy) was the sister of Edward Gordon Craig.
    - Craig, Edward Anthony. v.p., v.d.; (6 items) (Box 7, Folder 14)
      Edward Anthony Craig is the son of Edward Gordon Craig and Elena Meo Craig.
    - Craig, Elena Meo. v.p., v.d.; (9 items) (Box 7, Folder 15)
      Including sketches.
      The wife of Edward Gordon Craig and mother of E.A. Craig.
    - Ellis, Jane [Essy] London, 1879.; (1 item) (Box 7, Folder 16)
      Miss Ellis was Craig's nurse.
    - Henderson, F.R., and Son. Correspondence with Edward Gordon Craig. London, 1914.; (4 items) (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Holzapfel, Rudolf Melander. Paris, 1944-1948.; (3 items) (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Irving, Henry. Heidelberg, 1887.; (1 item) (Box 7, Folder 19)
      To Dear Hamlet.
    - Joseph, Helen Haiman. v.p., (?)., 1918-1926; (2 items, photocopy) (Box 7, Folder 19a)
    - Purcell Operatic Society. Hempstead, 1900.; (1 item) (Box 7, Folder 20)
      Includes sample of proposed stationery for the Society, designed by Craig.
    - St. John, Christopher. n.p., 1923.; (1 item) (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Terry, Ellen
      (See Box 8, below)
    - Unidentified. v.p., v.d.; (2 items) (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Craig, Elena Meo. Letter to Edith Craig. n.p., n.d.; (1 item) (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - de Walden, Lord Howard. Letter to Edward Gordon Craig. Suffolk, 1916.; (1 item) (Box 7, Folder 24)
      Lord de Walden was the primary backer for Craig's School for the Art of the Theatre.
    - Great Britain. War Office. Letter to Edward Gordon Craig. London, 1924.; (1 item) (Box 7, Folder 25)
      With holograph reply by Craig on reverse of letter.
    - Heythums. Letter to Edward Gordon Craig. Czechoslovakia, 1937.; (1 item) (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Nolan, James. Letter to Edward Gordon Craig. London, 1900.; (1 item) (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Shaw, Martin Fallas. Letter to Edward Gordon Craig. Hampstead, n.d.; (1 item) (Box 7, Folder 28)
      Martin Shaw was a composer and conductor; also a personal friend.
    - Whelen, Frederick. Letter to Edward Gordon Craig. London, 1915.; (1 item) (Box 7, Folder 29)
      With holograph comments by Craig.
    - Wimmer, Moritz. Letters to Edward Gordon Craig and Maurice Magnus. Berlin, 1904-1907.; (29 items) (Box 7, Folder 30)
      Letters written to Craig or Magnus, Craig's business partner, concerning backgrounds for stage performances. In German.
  - Craig, Edward Gordon. Correspondence with Ellen Terry. v.p., 1883-1923.; (125 items)
    Ellen Terry, the English dramatic actress, was the mother of Edward Gordon Craig. There are 7 letters from Ellen Terry to Gordon Craig; 115 letters from Gordon Craig to Ellen Terry; and 3 letters to Ellen Terry concerning Craig.
    - Letters from Edward Gordon Craig's years in boarding school., 1883-1888. (Box 8, Folder 1)
      13 letters from Craig to Ellen Terry; 2 to Ellen Terry concerning Craig.
    - Letters written while on tour with Henry Irving., 1889-1890. (Box 8, Folder 2)
      4 letters from Craig to Ellen Terry.
    - Letters written while on provincial tours., 1891. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Letter concerning Craig's production of A blot on the scutcheon., 1894. (Box 8, Folder 4)
      1 letter from Craig to Terry.
    - Letter concerning Gordon Craig's Book of Penny Toys and the periodical, The Page., 1899. (Box 8, Folder 5)
      1 letter from Craig to Ellen Terry.
    - Letters concerning theatrical collaboration between Craig and Ellen Terry: Dido and Aeneas; Masque of Love; Acis and Galatea., 1901-1902. (Box 8, Folder 6)
      4 letters from Ellen Terry to Craig and 5 from Craig to Ellen Terry.
    - Letters concerning theatrical collaboration: The Vikings; Bethlehem., 1903. (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Letters concerning The Art of the Theatre; George Bernard Shaw; and Bethlehem., 1904-1905. (Box 8, Folder 8)
      8 letters from Gordon Craig to Ellen Terry and 1 letter from Terry to Craig.
    - Letters concerning Sir Herbert Beerbohm Tree; George Bernard Shaw; Elenora Duse; Sarah Bernhardt; Isadora Duncan; and Craig's books, On the Art of the Theatre; and Scene., 1906-1907. (Box 8, Folder 9)
      5 letters from Craig to Ellen Terry.
    - Letters concerning the production of the Moscow Hamlet; Elektra; and Craig's periodical, The Mask., 1908-1909. (Box 8, Folder 10)
      6 letters from Craig to Ellen Terry.
    - Letters concerning the production of the Moscow Hamlet; Sir Herbert Beerbohm Tree's Macbeth; and George Bernard Shaw., 1910. (Box 8, Folder 11)
      14 letters from Craig to Ellen Terry and 1 letter to Ellen Terry concerning Gordon Craig.
    - Letters concerning the production of the Moscow Hamlet; Craig's books, On the Art of the Theatre and Scene; model stages and screens; and The Mask., 1911. (Box 8, Folder 12)
      12 letters from Craig to Ellen Terry.
    - Letters concerning Craig's School for the Art of the Theatre; the Cranach Press Hamlet; theory of the über-marionette., 1912. (Box 8, Folder 13)
      9 letters from Gordon Craig to Ellen Terry.
    - 1913. (Box 8, Folder 14)
      2 letters from Craig to Ellen Terry.
    - Letters concerning Craig's black figures., 1914. (Box 8, Folder 15)
      3 letters from Craig to Ellen Terry.
    - 1915. (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Letters concerning the Swiss set designer, Adolphe Appia., 1916. (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - 1917-1919. (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - A fragment from a letter to Ellen Terry by Craig with reference to the publication of Scene by the Clarendon Press., 1923. (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - n.d. (Box 8, Folder 20)
      7 letters from Gordon Craig to Ellen Terry.
- Section Six: Ephemera
  Oversize items shelved in Map Room, level B, Department of Special Collections.
  - Catalogues of Exhibitions by Edward Gordon Craig
    - Catalogue of etchings being designs for motions by Gordon Craig. Florence [Stabilimento Aldino], 1908.; (8 leaves) (Box 9, Folder 1)
      Text of forward in English and Italian.
    - Catalogue (2nd edition) of an exhibition of drawings and models for Hamlet and other plays by Edward Gordon Craig. London: Ernest Brown and Phillips, The Leicester Galleries, September 1912.; (12 leaves, Wrapper with device) (Box 9, Folder 2)
      Exhibition no.168.
    - Catalogue of an exhibition of drawings and models for Hamlet - Macbeth - The Vikings and other plays by Edward Gordon Craig. Manchester: City of Manchester Art Gallery, November 1912.; (41pp., Wrapper) (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Catalogue of an exhibition of drawings and models for Hamlet - Macbeth - The Vikings and other plays by Edward Gordon Craig. Leeds: The City Art Gallery, 1913.; (24pp., wrapper) (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - A catalogue of some designs by Edward Gordon Craig exhibited privately at 7 John Street, Adelphi, by the members of the School for the Art of the Theatre. [London]: School for the Art of the Theatre, July 6 to July 25, 1914.; (1 leaf. Loosely inserted into cover) (Box 9, Folder 5)
      Catalogue for first week only.
    - Wood engravings by E. Gordon Craig. London: The St. George's Gallery, June-July 1924.; (14pp., wrapper) (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Stage designs by Gordon Craig for The Pretenders by Ibsen, as produced at the State Theatre, Copenhagen, November 17, 1926, and etchings and other drawings. London: St. George's Gallery, June-July 1928.; (11pp., wrapper) (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Drawings and engravings by Edward Gordon Craig and some silverware by J. Paul Cooper and Francis Cooper. London: Ifan Kyrle Fletcher, June 14-July 16, 1938.; (13pp.) (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Nash, George. Edward Gordon Craig: 1872-1966. London: Her Majesty's Stationery Office, 1967.; (66pp.) (Box 9, Folder 9)
      Catalog of an exhibit held at the Victoria and Albert Museum, London.
    - Edward Gordon Craig: 1872-1966; Claud Lovat Fraser: 1890-1921. New York: Davis, Galleries, October 16, 1972-November 4, 1972.; (13pp.) (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Programs Designed by Edward Gordon Craig
    - Souvenir (). Acis and Galatea [and] Masque of Love as produced at the Great Queen Street Theatre, by Martin Shaw and Gordon Craig. [London: J.J. Waddington, ]., March 10, 1902 1902; (1 leaf and 34 leaves, with wrapper) (Box 9, Folder 11)
      Illustrated by Craig.
      With this: Souvenir. Acis and Galatea; Masque of Love, as produced at the Great Queen Street Theatre. Prospectus [London, 1902].
    - A Masque. The Harvest Home. Designed and arranged by Martin Shaw and Edward Gordon Craig. n.p., 1902.; (2 leaves) (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - A Matinee in Aid of the Ellen Terry Memorial. London, The Palace Theatre, Tuesday, April 23, 1929.; (16 leaves, wrapper) (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Publicity and Advertising Material: for Book Publications
    - The Art of the Theatre. Prospectus. London: T.N. Foulis, 1905.; (Postcard) (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - A portfolio of etchings. Prospectus. [Florence, ]., 1907; (2 leaves) (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - A second portfolio of etchings. Prospectus [Florence, ]., 1909; (2 leaves) (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Two portfolios of etchings. Prospectus [Florence, ]., 1910; (2 leaves) (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - On the Art of the Theatre. Prospectus. London: Heinemann, 1911.; (2 leaves) (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Towards a New Theatre. Prospectus. London: J.M. Dent & Sons, Limited, 1912.; (2 leaves) (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Scene. Prospectus. London: Oxford University Press, 1923.; (2 leaves) (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Woodcuts and Some Words. Advertisement. London: J.M. Dent & Sons, Limited, 1924.; (1 leaf) (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - [A production-1926] Gordon Craig in a theatre. Prospectus. London: Oxford University Press, 1930.; (2 leaves) (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Ellen Terry and her Secret Self. Prospectus. London: Sampson & Low, 1931.; (2 leaves) (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Fourteen notes. Prospectus. Seattle: University of Washington Bookstore, 1931.; (1 leaf) (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Gordon Craig and the theatre by Enid Rose. Prospectus. London: Sampson, Low, Marston & Company, 1931.; (2 leaves) (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Publicity and Advertising Material: for Periodicals Edited by Edward Gordon Craig
    - The Page. August announcement. Hackbridge, Surrey, 1899.; (2 leaves) (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - The Mask; a Monthly Journal of the Art of the Theatre. Announcement of appearance. Florence, March 1908.; (2 leaves) (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - The Mask; a Quarterly Journal of the Art of the Theatre. Prospectus. Florence, 1911.; (2 leaves) (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - The Mask; a Quarterly Journal of the Art of the Theatre. New Series. Prospectus for vol.4. Florence, 1911.; (8 leaves) (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - The Mask. Announcement of vol.4, no.4. Florence, April 1912.; (2 leaves) (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - The Mask. Announcement of vol.5, no.1. Florence, July 1912.; (2 leaves) (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - The Mask; a Quarterly Journal of the Art of the Theatre. Illustrated prospectus. Florence, 1912.; (2 leaves) (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - The Mask. Poster. Gordon Craig Defends Russian Ballet, illustrated by C. Lovat Fraser. Florence, 1913.; OVERSIZE ITEM E
      Refers to article by Craig in vol.6, no.1.
    - The Mask. Prospectus of vol.6, no.1. Florence, July 1913.; (1 leaf, 2 copies) (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - The Mask; a Quarterly Journal of the Art of the Theatre. Prospectus. Florence, 1909-1914.; (1 leaf) (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - The Mask and The Marionette. Announcement. Florence, March 1919.; (2 leaves) (Box 9, Folder 35)
    - The Mask; a Monthly Leaflet of the Art of the Theatre. Sample copy. Florence, April 1919.; (4 leaves. In wrapper. Inscribed on front flyleaf) (Box 9, Folder 36)
    - The Mask and The Marionette. Announcement. Florence, December 1920.; (1 leaf) (Box 9, Folder 37)
      A printed letter announcing a delay in resuming publication and stating that subscriptions were being deposited in a reserve fund during the war period.
    - The Mask; an Illustrated Journal of the Art of the Theatre. Prospectus. Florence, 1924.; (16pp.) (Box 9, Folder 38)
    - The Mask. Prospectus of vol.12 no.2. Florence, April 1926.; (2 leaves, 2 copies) (Box 9, Folder 39)
    - The Mask. A Journal of the Art of the Theatre. Poster. Florence, 1929.; OVERSIZE ITEM F (Box 28)
  - Publicity and Advertising Material: for Play Productions
    - Souvenir of The Dead Heart - presented at the Lyceum Theatre by Henry Irving. London: Cassel & Company, Limited, September 28, 1889.; (20 leaves) (Box 9, Folder 40)
      The part of Arthur de St. Valery was played by Craig.
    - Programs for stage performances with Edward Gordon Craig. London, Royal Lyceum Theatre, 1891-1896.; (3 items) (Box 9, Folder 41)
    - Souvenir of Becket - first presented at the Lyceum Theatre. London, February 6, 1893.; (18 leaves) (Box 9, Folder 42)
      The part of the youngest Knight Templar was played by Gordon Craig.
    - Hamlet. A benefit for Mr. Gordon Craig at the Paisley Theatre. Publicity card with woodcut by Craig on first page, Friday, July 26, 1895.; (2 leaves, mounted and framed with mat board) (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - Publicity and Advertising Material: for Miscellaneous Projects
    - Announcement. Hackbridge, Surrey, At the Sign of the Rose, 1901.; (4 leaves) (Box 9, Folder 44)
      Illustrated and printed by Gordon Craig
      It has for some considerable time been my wish to produce plays...
      Announcement of Craig's intention to manage stage productions if a sufficient show of support should be forthcoming.
    - Announcement. n.p., circa 1902; (1 leaf) (Box 9, Folder 45)
      Miss Edith Craig... is now prepared to carry out private orders for Ladie's Dresses...
      Illustrated and printed by Gordon Craig.
    - The Goldoni Books for artists. Advertisement. Florence, circa 1912.; (3 leaves, 2 items) (Box 9, Folder 46)
    - An exhibition of drawings and models for Hamlet - Macbeth - The Vikings and other plays by Edward Gordon Craig. Poster. Leeds: The City Art Gallery, 1913.; OVERSIZE ITEM G
    - The School for the Art of the Theatre. Announcement of purpose. London: Chiswick Press, 1913.; (7pp., 2 copies) (Box 9, Folder 47)
    - The School for the Art of the Theatre. Subscription form. n.p., 1913.; (3 leaves) (Box 9, Folder 48)
      Noted for private circulation.
      With subscription forms loosely inserted.
    - The Society of the Theatre, affiliated to the Gordon Craig School of the Art of the Theatre. Announcement of purpose. London, 1913.; (2 leaves, 2 copies) (Box 9, Folder 49)
    - The Society of Wood Engravers. Invitation to an exhibition. London: The St. George's Gallery, December 1923.; (1 item) (Box 9, Folder 50)
    - Booksellers' catalogues offering for sale material relating to Gordon Craig. v.p., v.d.; (5 items) (Box 9, Folder 51)
  - Press Clippings
    - Articles and letters to the editor written by Gordon Craig. v.p., v.d.; (6 items) (Box 10, Folder 1)
      Including two articles.
      - On stage scenery. In The Morning Post. London, October 13, 1903.; (1 leaf, clipping) (Box 10, Folder 1)
        With holograph comment by Ellen Terry.
      - Monumenta Scenica; a review by Gordon Craig. In The Observer. London, April 4, 1926.; (1 leaf, clipping) (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Designs, critical reviews of Craig's designs and exhibits. v.p., v.d.; (42 items) (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Personal and family clippings. v.p., v.d.; (20 items) (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Productions staged and designed by Edward Gordon Craig. v.p., v.d.; Oversize item H; (46 items) (Box 10, Folder 4 - 6 and)
      - Acis and Galatea; The Masque of Love. As presented at The Great Queen Street Theatre. London, March 10, 1902.; (10 items) (Box 26, Folder 4)
      - Bethlehem. As presented at the Imperial Institute, December 1902.; (5 items) (Box 26, Folder 5)
      - Hamlet. As presented at the Moscow Art Theatre, December 1911-January 1912.; (30 items) (Box 26, Folder 6)
        Press clippings and advertising material relating to Craig's former work and present designs for the production.
        - Press clippings. Moscow, In Russian., 1911-1912.; (10 items) (Box 26, Folder 6)
        - Postcards. Moscow, 1912.; (20 items in wrapper) (Box 26, Folder 6)
          Photographs of the actors in the Moscow production by K.A. Fetser.
      - The Vikings. As presented at the Imperial Theatre. London, April 15, 1903-May 9, 1903.; OVERSIZE ITEM H; (1 item, scrapbook)
        Scrapbook: Miss Ellen Terry's Season, Imperial Theatre, 1903.
        Contains 67 leaves of press clippings pertaining to The Vikings.
        Production staged by Gordon Craig, Ellen Terry as Hiordis.
    - Publications. Criticism of publications by or with contributions by Craig. v.p., 1903-1930.; (11 items) (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - The School for the Study of the Art of the Theatre. London, 1904.; (4 items) (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Theatrical criticism, general, with reference to Craig. v.p., 1903-1930.; (28 items) (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Biographical material. v.p., 1966-.; (2 items) (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous Ephemera
    - Miscellaneous ephemera. v.p., v.d.; (10 items) (Box 10, Folder 11)
- Section Seven: Photographs
  - Photographs of Miscellaneous and Unidentified Designs by Craig
    - Miscellaneous (Box 11)
      - D'Artagnan's man., 1898. (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - Thatchley. Suffolk., 1903. (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - Che peccato, or, La Donna di Zena., 1905. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Unidentified
      - Child in robe and sun hat., 1902. (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - Costumed male figure with staff., 1902. (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - King and supplicant., 1903. (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - Stylized profile of woman in ornamental cap., 1908. (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - Figure in white on staircase., 1909. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Photographs of Puppets and Masks
    - Pagoda scene. Mandalay., circa 1890. (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Mask., 1913. (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Groups of masks., 1913.; (3 items) (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Puppets., 1913.; (5 items) (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Puppet., 1913.; (Mounted photograph) (Box 11, Folder 3)
      Inscribed Teddy from India, from Gordon Craig to his son, E.A. Craig.
  - Photographs of Model Stages and Figures
    - Five puppets designed and made by EGC, 1907... behind is a scene... [Florence]., (Mounted photograph) (Box 11, Folder 4)
      Holograph notes on mount.
    - Hamlet. Figures in the graveyard scene. n.p., circa 1909. (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Hamlet. Act 4, scene 6. n.p., circa 1909 (Box 11, Folder 4)
      Holograph notes on photograph.
    - Model stage with figure to left of dais. n.p. Dated by Craig, 1911. (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Model stage for Hamlet. Three views. n.p., 1913. (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Model stage. Proscenium. n.p., 1914. (Box 11, Folder 4)
      Two explanatory notes in Craig's hand.
    - Model stage with figures. n.p., n.d.; (Mounted) (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Model stage with figures. n.p., n.d.; (Mounted) (Box 11, Folder 5)
      With holograph note by Craig on the mount.
    - Photographs of model for St. Matthew's Passion [not produced] Florence., 1914.; (4 views) (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Photographs of Designs for Productions
    - The Masque of Love., 1901.; (3 items) (Box 11, Folder 7)
      - A pierrot. (Box 11, Folder 7)
      - Comus. Mask. (Box 11, Folder 7)
      - King and queen. (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Bethlehem; a nativity play., 1902.; (3 items) (Box 11, Folder 8)
      - Three king's head dresses drawn on one sheet. (Box 11, Folder 8)
      - A shepherd. (Box 11, Folder 8)
      - Young shepherd. (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Acis and Galatea., 1902.; (4 items) (Box 11, Folder 9)
      - Act 1. Scene 1., (Signed, noted and colored on photograph) (Box 11, Folder 9)